<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: HTML | Cleo Ceg blog.]]></title>
  <link href="http://cleoceg.github.io/blog/categories/html/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://cleoceg.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-06-17T21:50:51+02:00</updated>
  <id>http://cleoceg.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Cleo Ceggrers]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Something About Markdown]]></title>
    <link href="http://cleoceg.github.io/blog/2013/06/17/something-about-markdown/"/>
    <updated>2013-06-17T20:57:00+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://cleoceg.github.io/blog/2013/06/17/something-about-markdown</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The purpose of Markdown</p>

<blockquote><p>June 17, 2013</p></blockquote>

<p>Markdown is an easy to read and write language which emulate a sort of HTML-light-tags. You can find a more precise description of it (Don&rsquo;t Repeat Yourself &ndash; DRY) at <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Markdown">wikipedia</a>.</p>

<p>Already nine years old and not even an existing and approved RFC or draft of standard. It&rsquo;s have already great support from lively projects like GitHub and Stack Overflow. You can see a good post on the subject at <a href="http://www.codinghorror.com/blog/2012/10/the-future-of-markdown.html">coding Horror</a> where Jeff Atwood is proposing to bring forth a formal standard. For now I don&rsquo;t know the status of this project/idea.</p>

<p>For my point of view I use Markdown with vim as a plugin. I find an entry point at <a href="http://www.vim.org/scripts/script.php?script_id=1242">vim.org</a> and rely on the post of <a href="http://plasticboy.com/markdown-vim-mode/">PlasticBoy</a> to put it in my editor-sidekick: VIM. Although I&rsquo;ve tried a more featured version of a dedicated editor for Markdown <a href="http://markdownpad.com/news/2013/introducing-markdownpad-2/">MarkdownPad</a>. You can use the latter to view what your write in markdown tags and how it&rsquo;ll be displayed in an HTML page. It is shipped with a free and a pro (but you must paid for it) version.</p>

<p>And last but not least this website <a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/">DaringFireball</a> give the official outlines of markdown &ldquo;standard&rdquo;</p>

<p>In Fact the only important question is: when does Markdown become a formal standard?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
